

# Rob Pataki

## Freelance Front-end developer

Based in London, Brick Lane rob@handcrafted.studio

#### **About**

I am a Freelance Front-end developer with 10+ years of UI design and animation experience; and 5+ years experience in building interactive multimedia applications using open HTML technologies. I specialise in building responsive web applications with the main focus on seamless, performant user experiences and interactive animations.

Being a freelancer gives me the perfect opportunity to help businesses and creative agencies. I use my expertise to give their web based products a smooth user experience in desktop browsers, and to make them feel native on handheld devices. I enjoy taking ownership of small projects, as well as working on bigger projects as part of a team. I am always looking for new challenges, and I am keen to learn new technologies, improve my skills and meet awesome people.

In my free time I am slapping my bass, going to live gigs, do yoga, and I am perfecting my vegan cooking skills.

#### **Skills**

### Coding Skills

HTML, vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, animation, MV\*?\$# framework, (and I do a bit of PHP and Ruby too), unit tests

Most used JavaScript Libraries

Greensock, PIXI, FastClick, Underscore, jQuery, Brewser

Preferred MV\* Frameworks

Custom framework using requirejs/CommonJS best practices, Angular, Backbone

Preferred Preprocessors and Task Runners

Static templating tools (Nunjacks, Handlebars, Jekyll), LibSass + Bourbon for CSS, Gulp/WebPack/Browserify, Grunt/Bower/Yeoman, Ruby on Rails

#### **Preferred Tools**

Chrome, Terminal, Git, Sublime Text 3, MacDown, Photoshop, Illustrator, Invision, DropMark, Slack, Project Management tools (Trello, Jira, Assembla, Pivotal Tracker), Harvest

**Experience** 

Freelance Front-end developer

06/2013 - Today

I have been working with inspiring teams such as **ustwo Studio**, **Reform London**, **Crew Studio** on projects for distinguished clients like **Oakley**, **Barclays**, **Nissan**, and **Unilever**.

Front-end developer

Unboxed Consulting, London UK

04/2012 - 06/2013

At Unboxed I worked with a bunch of super talented Ruby developers in a completely agile environment, where I learnt loads about **Git**, **scrum**, **TDD**, **BDD** and many more. During my time there I was mainly working on client side as part of a big agile team working on products such as the **FutureLearn** website, some **GDS** products, or the **Channel Five** website.

Creative Technologist

Waste Creative, London UK

10/2009 - 04/2012

I finally decided to move to London and I landed a job at the awesome team of Waste Creative. With clients such as **Sega**, **British Gas**, **Fiction Records**, **Cartoon Network** and **Disney**, I had lots of opportunities to learn new skills, perfect my English, and start the transition of moving away from **Flash** towards the more open **HTML** technologies.

Lead product designer / Flash developer

Artklikk, Budapest HUN

04/2009 - 10/2009

UI Designer / Flash animator & developer

Naiad Interactive, Budapest HUN

12/2008 - 04/2009

Clients: Magyar Telekom, Budapest Card, The German National Tourist Board

UI Designer / Flash animator & developer

Carussel Group, Budapest HUN

04/2012 - 06/2013

Clients: Opel, Porsche, Audi, Seat, Volkswagen

UI designer / Flash animator & developer

Carnation, Budapest HUN

05/2006 - 02/2007

Clients: Telenor, Nivea, Microsoft, Bosch, Honda

Education

SZÁMALK Budapest - Multimedia Technology: HND, 2006

**Client projects** 

Amplify (responsive website build, UI interface modules, animations)

http://www.weareamplify.com/

Sang Bleu Club (responsive website build, UI interface modules)

https://sangbleu.club

Oakley Disruptogram (responsive website build)

http://disruptogr.am

FutureLearn (setup, responsive website build)

https://www.futurelearn.com/

Open source projects

Greenock-JS Ruby gem

https://github.com/robertpataki/greensock-rails

Brewser.js

https://github.com/robertpataki/brewser

Brewser.js Demo

http://robertpataki.github.io/brewser/

Yeoman generator: Sizzle

https://github.com/robertpataki/generator-sizzle